A Guide to the Papers of Dr. Edward Watson Hook, Jr., 1947-1998
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- SERIES 4: Office Files, alphabetically arranged
  - Grand Rounds September 1980-February 1990, 9 TD, 35 TLS, 8 TL, 16 TMemo, 1 Article, 1 AN, 1 TDS, 1 TN, 2 TMemoS (Box-folder 024-008)
    Re: Participation, speakers, and evaluations of Grand Rounds.
  - Grand Rounds, Protocols July 1980-May 1988, 30 TD, 1 Article (Box-folder 024-009)
    Re: UVa patient cases and discussion of disease and treatments in the grand rounds of the Department of Internal Medicine.
  - Health Sciences, Assistant Vice-President February 1975-February 1981, 19 TL, 33 TLS, 1 TD, 3 TMemo, 1 AN (Box-folder 024-010)
    Re: Primarily Hook's correspondence with Donald J. Wright and Jules I. Levine concerning needs of the Medical Center.
  - Health Sciences Center, Senior Associate Vice President May 1988-July 1990, 11 TLS, 1 AN, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 024-011)
    Re: Hiring Robert Reynolds and securing office and bed space.
  - Health Science Center, Vice-President July 1987-May 1990, 43 TLS, 3 ALS, 2 TL, 4 TMemo, 1 TMemoS, 3 TD, 1 TMs, 1 Article (Box-folder 024-012)
    Re: Chiefly correspondence between Hook and Don E. Detmer, Vice President for Health Sciences and includes discussion about the medical center name change to Health Sciences Center and distribution of a generous gift by Madge Jones.
  - Health Services Foundation, Correspondence (1985-1986) April 1985-August 1986, 14 TLS, 1 TMemo, 1 TMemoS, 8 TD (Box-folder 024-013)
    Re: Discussions about disability plan, department deficits, organization structures of UVa Health Services foundation & affiliated foundations & committee structure.
  - Health Services Foundation February 1987-July 1990, 42 TLS, 4 TD, 5 TMemo (Box-folder 025-001)
    Re: Miscellaneous issues: Signing checks, professional fees policy, loan funding, retirement plans, billing from Health services, & classification of patients.
  - Health Services Foundation, Billing System January 1981-September 1985, 2 TMemo, 2 TD, 5 TLS, 1 Bill (Box-folder 025-002)
    Re: Discussion about billing system of UVa hospital & foundation.
  - Health Services Foundation, Budget January 1982-May 1986, 2 TL, 3 TD, 3 TLS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 025-003)
    Re: Expenditures of Health Services funds.
  - Health Services Foundation: Bylaws December 1987-June 1988, 9 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 025-004)
    Re: Munsey Wheby is a part of a committee to reevaluate the bylaws of the Health Services Foundation.
  - Health Services Foundation, Fringe Benefits October 1981-July 1990, 9 TMemo, 20 TLS, 7 TL, 4 TD, 1TDS, 1 TMs, 1 TDw/AN (Box-folder 025-005)
    Re: Fringe benefits package for faculty such as life insurance, disability, and travel insurance. Included is a 1983 report of the Faculty Fringe Benefits Committee.
  - Health Services April 1989-November 1989, 6 TLS (Box-folder 025-006)
    Re: Deals with a job description of Executive Director of the Foundation and Hewitt's Incentive Plan Design.
  - Health Services Foundation, Legal Matters September 1982-December 1989, 1 TL, 3 TMemo, 2 TLS (Box-folder 025-007)
    Re: Medical Malpractice.
  - Health Services Foundation, Malpractice September 1969-January 1990, 6 TL, 7 TMemo, 12 TLS, 5 TD, 1 TMs (Box-folder 025-008)
    Re: Evolution of malpractice insurance in UVa Hospital from in 1969 not all house staff covered by insurance to the premiums listed in 1990.
  - Helicopter Transport System February 1983-March 1983, 1 TLS, 2 TLS (Box-folder 025-009)
    Re: Hook favors a helicopter system.
  - Helix June 1986-June 1989, 6 TLS, 1 TL (Box-folder 025-010)
    Re: Hook wants editors to identify staff's names and titles under photographs published in the Helix.
  - Hematology-Oncology Unit (Blue Ridge) May 1982-August 1986, 3 TLS, 1 TMemo, 2 TD (Box-folder 025-011)
    Re: Outline of needs establishing a Palliative Care Inpatient Program at Blue Ridge facility and concerns placing an oncology unit physically adjacent to a TB Unit.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1982 February 1980-December 1982, 3 TL, 19 TLS, 3 TD, 4 TMemo, 1 ANS, 2 Maps (Box-folder 025-012)
    Re: Hook's correspondence with Peter Quesenberry, Chief of Hematology/Oncology Division, includes concerns about clinical coverage, research development, finances, and space.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1983 January-December 1983, 1 TMemoS, 2 TL, 6 TLS, 2 TMemo, 1 ALS, 1 TMs (Box-folder 025-013)
    Re: Documents include how to fully utilize the Oncology department and includes documents relating to nurses handling anticarcinogenic medications.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1984 January-December 1984, 11 TLS, 1 TL (Box-folder 025-014)
    Re: Documents include discussion about fellows, workshops, faculty appointments, and the importance of the bone marrow transplantation program.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1985 January-November 1985, 9 TLS (Box-folder 025-015)
    Re: Discussions cover colorectal screening clinic, case information, handling pediatric marrow transplants, and funding for research.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1986 January-November 1986, 11 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TNS, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 025-016)
    Re: Decline in out-patient visits at Blue Ridge Hospital, summary outline of growth factor program project, and office and lab space issues.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division on, Correspondence, 1987 January-December 1987, 11 TLS (Box-folder 025-017)
    Re: Future of oncology at Blue Ridge Hospital, new initiatives for hematology/oncology, filling faculty positions, and salary and space discussions.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1988 January-December 1988, 25 TLS, 5 TD (Box-folder 025-018)
    Re: Peter Quesenberry, Professor and Chief Division of Hematology/Oncology addresses space needs, AIDS work at Blue Ridge, recruitment, and outpatient operation.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1989 January-December 1989, 44 TLS, 2 TL, 1 TNS, 4 TD, 2 TMemo, 1 ANS (Box-folder 025-019)
    Re: Faculty appointments and funding issues, space issues for the Marrow Transplant Laboratory, patient surveys, patient case issues instigated by concerns raised by Hook, and financial concerns in the Division of Hematology and Oncology.
  - Hematology/Oncology, Division of, Correspondence, 1990 January-July 1990, 28 TLS, 3 graphs, 1 TL, 4 TMemo, 3 TDS (Box-folder 025-020)
    Re: Space issues including clinic overcrowding, contract between UVa Health Sciences Center and Rockingham Memorial Hospital, faculty promotion and salary raises, and "code status" of patients.
  - Hospice April 1983-April 1989, 3 TLS (Box-folder 026-001)
    Re: Hook desires a hospice in the new hospital.
  - Hospital, Associate Hospital Director December 1974-December 1989, 11 TLS, 2 TL (Box-folder 026-002)
    Re: Hook correspondence addresses fire safety in stairways, family lounges, bed availability, and the physical appearance of the building.
  - Hospital, Bed census-correspondence June 1984-October 1990, 19 TLS, 3 TMemoS, 1 TMemo, 13 TD, 2 TL, 4 graphs (Box-folder 026-003)
    Re: Correspondence regarding updating bed needs of the institution and includes descriptions of bed allotments, charts, graphs, and statistics.
  - Hospital, Bed census (Blue Ridge Hospital) January 1984-January 1986, 2 TMemo, 12 TD, 1 TMs, 1 TLS (Box-folder 026-004)
    Re: Hook encourages the consolidation of the beds at Blue Ridge and UVA hospital; documents include a report entitled, "Blue Ridge Hospital Report of the Tuberculosis Service Fiscal year 1982 July 1, 1981 - June 30, 1982."
  - Hospital, Bed Census: Annual Statistical Reports May 1974-January 1990, 3 TL, 6 TD, 8 TLS, 1 TNw/AN, 2 TMemoS, 1 TD w/AN, 2 ALS, 1 graph, 1 AD (Box-folder 026-005)
    RE: Bed utilization and clinical reports of admissions.
  - Hospital (UVa), Budget December 1981-February 1989, 9 TMemo, 14 TLS, 15 TD, 3 TL, 1 AD, 4 Reports, 3 Graphs (Box-folder 026-006)
    Re: Budget issues and concerns including graphs, charts and statistics of admissions, budgets, and actual costs.
  - Hospital, Capital Outlay Program for 1990-2000 April-June 1988, 3 TMemo, 2 TD, 6 TLS, 22 TDS, 2 ALS (Box-folder 026-007)
    Re: Hook submits proposals from the departments in Internal Medicine for the capital outlay budget for 1990-2000 in which department head details specific needs and wants for each department.
  - Hospital, Comptroller for Medical Affairs July 1970-September 1984, 15 TLS, 32 TL, 3 TMemo, 6 TD, 1 Invoice, 2 Work orders, 1 journal article (1st page) (Box-folder 026-008)
    Re: Correspondence (mostly from the 1970s) includes discussions on overhead funds, professional fee schedules, funding for specific needs with the departments of Internal Medicine and for improvements in the facility, expense of long distance telephone calls, and fringe benefits for faculty.
  - Hospital-Uva, Capital Outlay Projections November 1968-May 1988, 2 TMs, 1 TMemo, 1 TMemoS, 1 ALS, 3 TLS (Box-folder 026-009)
    Re: Includes "Proposed 1970-1980 Capital Outlay Projections and Program" and "Planning Guidelines for the Ten-Year Capital Budget 1988-1998."
  - Hospital (UVa)-Director September 1969-December 1976, 45 TL, 16 TLS, 10 TD, 4 TMemo, 1 AD (Box-folder 026-010)
    Re: Correspondence with John F. Harlan, Jr., Director, University of Virginia Hospital includes increasing residency programs, patient care and comfort, faculty appointments, and addition of beds.
  - Hospital (UVa)-Director January 1977-November 1981, 47 TL, 12 TLS, 2 TDS, 3 TD, 4 TMemo, 1 AD, 2 TMs (Box-folder 026-011)
    Re: Correspondence mostly with John F. Harlan, Jr. Director, UVA Hospitals includes lack of storage, shortage of beds, patient care and amenities, visitor control, canceling and rescheduling patients, use of the Towers Hospital, and accreditation awards.
  - Hospital (UVa), Director-Correspondence December 1981-November 1985, 15 TLS, 3 TL, 1 TLS, 4 TMemoS, 1 TD (Box-folder 026-012)
    Re: Correspondence with John T. Ashley, Director, UVA Hospital, includes teaching funds, identification photographs, swing beds, cleaning, storage, and maintenance problems, and dissatisfaction with managerial process.
  - Hospital (UVa) Director-Correspondence December 1985-August 1986, 27 TLS, 1 TMemo, 1 ALS, 1 TD (Box-folder 027-001)
    Re: Correspondence with John T. Ashley about home health care program, foundation to deliver patient care services outside the Hospitals, ambulatory internal medicine, prescription liability, subsidizing primary care practitioners, administrative duties, laboratory costs, maintaining quality services, and a grant proposal for General Electric Foundation.
  - Hospital (UVa) Director-Correspondence February-December 1987, 1 TMs, 16 TLS, 4 TMemo, 1 TD (Box-folder 027-002)
    Re: Hook's notes after a meeting with John T. Ashley who proposed cutting costs by 7 million dollars, loss of referral physicians, delinquent medical records, obtaining a pager, ambulatory care leadership, patient costs, and Blue Ridge Hospital.
  - Hospital (UVa) Director-Correspondence January-October 1988, 10 TLS, 1 ALS, 1 TL (Box-folder 027-003)
    Re: Topics include acquisition of a Gamma Unit, praise from a satisfied patient, problems with the Simon Paging System, Nephrology residents, and food and drink restriction policy.
  - Hospital (UVa), Director-Correspondence January-November 1989, 5 TMemo, 22 TLS, 1 TD, 2 ALS (Box-folder 027-004)
    Re: Obtaining admission lists, availability of beds, budget adjustments, enhancing revenue, removal of vending machines, difficulty of maintaining adequate amount of nurses, and the appointment of Michael J. Halseth as interim executive director.
  - Hospital (UVa), Director-Correspondence January-June 1990, 2 TMemo, 19 TLS, 1 TL (Box-folder 027-005)
    Re: Surgical Transition Lounge, unlocked file cabinets, last pod on 8th floor, relationship between Augusta Hospital Corporation and UVA Hospital, additional residents, placement of directory signs, movement of departments, and various "housekeeping items."
  - Hospital, Executive Management Program December 1986-February 1987, 4 TMemo, 3 TD (Box-folder 027-006)
    Re: Improving productivity and reducing costs throughout the hospital.
  - Hospital (UVa), General June 1982-November 1984, 22 TLS, 3 TL, 4 TMemo, 18 TD (Box-folder 027-007)
    Re: Admissions, organizational charts, and lists of departments and managers by division, complaints by overcrowding, lack of cleanliness and inadequate patient care, discharge summaries, audit, and graphs and charts dealing with cash flow projections.
  - Hospital (UVa), General January 1985-February 1990, 8 TMemo, 8 graphs, 34 TLS, 8 TD, 1 AN, 1 TMs, 1 TL (Box-folder 027-008)
    Re: Service-specific admission and patient days graphs, internal audit, revision of hospital organization, Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report 1986-1998, hospital nutrition center, surgical furlough policy, notification program, North 4 patient care unit, and space issues.
  - Hospital (UVa, General-History 1958, 1961, 1975, 3 publications (Box-folder 027-009)
    Re: 1958, "We're Going to Have A New Hospital"; "New Hospital Dedicated, April 14, 1961"; "The Early Years of The University of Virginia Hospital: An Analysis of Patient's Records."
  - Hospital (UVa), JCAH Accreditation December 1981-July 1990, 1 TD, 2 TMs, 1 TL, 3 TLS, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 027-010)
    Re: Information collected through Hook's years for evaluation by Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals; included is a 1981 recommendation for future compliance and 1990 Mock Survey for JCAHO.
  - Hospital (UVa), Long Range Planning May-August 1986, 2 TLS (Box-folder 027-011)
    Re: Hook comments in depth on the 1985 Hospital Long Range Plan.
  - Hospital, Roanoke/Salem Correspondence March 1971-March 1987, 5 TD, 20 TL, 29 TLS, 1 TMs, 1 TN, 1 magazine advertisement, 3 TMemoS (Box-folder 027-012)
    Re: Correspondence regarding University of Virginia relationship between Veterans Administration Hospital, Salem, Virginia and Roanoke Memorial Hospital, Roanoke, Virginia.
  - Hospital, Rockingham Memorial Hospital February 1988-March 1990, 1 TMemo, 5 TLS, 1 TMs, 2 AD, 1 TDS (Box-folder 027-013)
    Re: 1988 proposed agreement between Rockingham Memorial Hospital, Harrisonburg, Virginia and UVA Hospitals.
  - Hospital, Towers March 1982-February 1987, 1 TL, 1 TD, 10 TMemo, 3 TLS (Box-folder 027-014)
    Re: The Towers were used as rehabilitation units in the early 1980's; by 1988 the University terminated the lease of the Towers.
  - Hospital, Towers (Extended Care Facility) September 1969-November 1974, 15 TL, 4 TMemo, 16 TLS, 1 TD w/AN, 4 TD, 1 TMs (Box-folder 027-015)
    Re: Development of the Extended Care Facility in the Towers which opened in the fall of 1971; concern about railroad noise, locating student health services in ECF, house staff coverage, transportation difficulties, the towers fee schedule, tower's statistics, laboratory space for Department of Pathology, and indigent care.
  - Hospital (UVa), Towers (Continuing Care Facility) November 1971-July 1975, 7 TLS, 7 TL, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 027-016)
    Re: Topics involving the Towers, such as stocking periodicals and textbooks about chronic diseases, organization of the Medical Services in CCF, house staff coverage, Family Practice Program involvement, transportation of patients, and relationship to endocrine laboratory.
  - Hospital (UVa)-Towers June 1975-December 1981, 2 TD, 26 TL, 18 TLS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 028-001)
    Re: Documents include tower statistics for 1975 & 1976. Hook also details difficulties in the operation of the Towers which include refusal of residents/staff to see patients, nursing shortage and small nursing station, dietary problems, transportation difficulties, inadequate procedural rooms, and use of patient lounges by staff.
  - House Staff Survey Thru 1971 [n.d.], 3 AD, 4 TMs (Box-folder 028-002)
    Re: 3 hand-written documents about resident statistics and 4 manuscripts including "Number of House Staff Trained at UVA Medical Center During the Past 20 Years"; "Proposed Plan for the Medical HouseStaff for 1971-72"; "Survey of House Staff Training at UVA"; "Graduates of UVA School Of Medicine".
  - Humanities in Literature April 1992-1995, 8 TLS, 1 TL, 1 TDS, 23 TD, 4 TMs, 1 AD (Box-folder 028-003)
    Re: Includes essays written by Hook and others dealing with medical issues in humanities and also evaluations of Hook's elective, "Film, Literature, and the Visual Art: Images in Medicine".
  - Humanities, "Images of Medicine in Film, Visual Arts, & Literature" August-Sept 1998, 1 TMs (Box-folder 028-004)
    Re: Hook's course syllabus.
  - Hunter, Thomas September 1980-March 1994, 1 TD, 1 TDS, 22 TD w/ AN, 1 photograph, 4 AD, 1 TMs (Box-folder 028-005)
    Re: Documents include the interview questions for nineteen sessions that Hook conducted with Dr. Thomas Hunter. (Tapes can be found in the Papers of Thomas Hunter, Historical Collections & Services.) Also included is excerpts from Hunter's diary.
  - Infectious Diseases December 1979-December 1987, 11 TL, 33 TLS, 2 TD, 1 AL, 1 TNS, 1 AN, 1 brochure, 5 TMemo, 1 TMs (Box-folder 028-006)
    Re: Correspondence primarily with Gerald L. Mandell, Head, Division of Infectious Diseases, included is Hook's biennial report for 1986.
  - Infectious Diseases November 1969-April 1989, 8 TMemo, 37 TL, 36 TLS, 8 TD, 2 TMs, 1 AN, 1 AL (Box-folder 028-007)
    Re: Correspondence with Mandell includes problems with the microbiology lab, funding issues, patient cases, recruitment of faculty, space demands, and purchasing of equipment.
  - Infectious Diseases, 1989 March 1989-January 1990, 1 TD, 1 TL, 12 TLS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 028-008)
    Re: Aids Center, Lilly Research grant, and continued accreditation.
  - Infectious Disease Subspecialty Fellowship Program/Roanoke/Salem April 5-19, 1983, 5 TLS, 1 TL, 1 TMemoS, 1 TMs (Box-folder 028-009)
    Re: Plans for a fellowship program.
  - Information Sciences and Biostatistics November 1986-December 1988, 52 TLS, 1 TMemoS, 1 TL, 1 TNS, 1 TN, 1 Map, 1 TD (Box-folder 029-001)
    Re: Primarily Hook's correspondence with Donald L. Kaiser, Head, Division of Information Sciences and Biostatistics. Discussions include the development of a medical information sciences department, recruitment of a biostatistician, purchasing of software programs, and budgetary support.
  - Information Sciences and Biostatistics February-November 1987, 35 TLS, 5 TMemo, 2 TD, 1 ALS (Box-folder 029-002)
    Re: A request for high-powered computing facilities is not seen necessary by many division heads. The department of information sciences is dissolved and renamed Division of Biostatistics under the director of Robert Abbott.
  - Information Services (Public Relations) April 1982-April 1988, 10 TLS, 5 TD, 1 TMemo, 1 ALS (Box-folder 029-003)
    Re: Press releases about book published on Walter Reed, intestinal diseases in Brazil, Hook's honorary doctor of medical science degree, and an interview of Hook by the Medical Examiner.
  - Intensive Care Unit June 1970-August 1977, 7 TMemo, 14 TLS, 9 TL, 4 TD, 7 Maps, 1 ALS, 4 TDS, 1 ADS, 1 AD (Box-folder 029-004)
    Re: Proposal of plans for intensive care in the 1970s and the implementation of those plans.
  - Intensive Care Unit May 1978-January 1982, 23 TLS, 7 TMemo, 1 TMs, 8 TD, 3 TN, 11 TL, 1 AN (Box-folder 029-005)
    Re: Status of MICU, the serious need for medical intensive care unit, census of patients in MICU, the opening of the MICU in the early 1980s, admission criteria and operational guidelines, patient cases and patient care. Hook corresponds primarily with C. Edward Rose, Jr, Director, MICU.
  - Intensive Care Unit, Correspondence April 1982-March 1988, 8 TLS, 1 TL, 1 TNS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 029-006)
    Re: Critical care topics include neonotal ICU, No code orders, lack of nurses, and utilizing MICU for stroke patients.
  - Informed Consent January- pril 1981, 1 TD, 1 TMs, 1 TLS (Box-folder 029-007)
    Re: Guidelines for obtaining consent to medical treatment.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Report May 1950-1955, 8 TLS, 3 TL, 15 TD, 1 TMemo, 1 TMs (Box-folder 029-008)
    Re: Fiscal reports of Internal medicine under Dr. William Parson.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Report 1955-1956, 12 TD, 2 TLS, 4 TL, 1 TMs (Box-folder 029-009)
    Re: Fiscal report material for 1955-1956.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Report January 1959-1960, 1 TL, 2 TMs (Box-folder 029-010)
    Re: Reports for fiscal year 1958, & 1959-1960.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Reports 1961-1964, 5 TMs, 2 TD (Box-folder 029-011)
    Re: Reports to the President from Internal medicine for the years 1961-1964.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Reports 1963-1965, 2 TMs, 1 TD (Box-folder 029-012)
    Re: Reports of Internal Medicine for fiscal years 64-65.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Report 1961-1967, 4 TD, 3 TMs (Box-folder 029-013)
    Re: Annual Reports for 1966 & 1967.
  - Internal Medicine, Annual Report 1968, 1 TMs (Box-folder 029-014)
    Re: 1968 annual report.
  - Martha Jefferson Hospital December 1967-January 1984, 4 TMemo, 6 TD, 12 TL, 11 TLS, 1 ALS, 1 TN (Box-folder 030-001)
    Re: Intern training and Director of Education in Internal Medicine at Martha Jefferson Hospital.
  - Johnson Fdn. Grants ?1973-December 1984, 4 TD, 22 TLS, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 030-002)
    Re: Grant from Robert Wood Johnson Foundation for development of primary care program.
  - Johnson, L.B. April-June 1972, 1 TLS, 2 TL (Box-folder 030-003)
    Re: Thank you from L.B.J.'s doctor for good treatment.
  - Laboratory, Clinical March 1973-May 1990, 12 TL, 1 TN, 3 TD, 15 TLS, 1 TMs, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 030-004)
    Re: Complaints about clinical laboratory, establishment of an advisory committee, confining budgetary and personnel constraints, 'stat' basis for laboratory work, and a 1979 "Report in Regard to Clinical Laboratory Services at the University of Virginia Medical Center Charlottesville".
  - Laboratories (Floor) February 1980-January 1986, 3 TMemo, 1 TD, 11 TLS, 1 TL (Box-folder 030-005)
    Re: Minutes regarding laboratory fees, feasibility of maintaining "floor" laboratories, and renal labs.
  - Laboratories: Outside laboratory utilization February 1981-July 1987, 42 TLS, 1 ALS, 11 TD, 1 TDS, 5 TL, 6 TMemo, 1 TMs, 1 ALS (Box-folder 030-006)
    Re: Includes a 1983 "Report of the Outside Laboratory Utilization Task Force to the Medical Policy Committee"; also discussions about sending specimens to outside laboratories.
  - Laboratory, Special Function June 1987-December 1989, 22 TLS, 1 TL, 2 TMemo, 1 TD, 1 TD w/AN (Box-folder 030-007)
    Re: Hook strongly supported maintaining special laboratories within Internal Medicine; the hospital director, John Ashley, did not.
  - Lasker Foundation - Medical Journalism Awards Committee November 1969-September 1972, 6 TL, 10 TLS, 2 TD, 1 pamphlet, 1 newspaper clipping (photocopy) (Box-folder 030-008)
    Re: Hook serves on the Albert Lasker Awards in Medical Journalism jury.
  - Legal Case-Hedge v. United States August 1988-February 1989, 6 TLS, 4 TD, 1 AN, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 030-009)
    Re: Hook provides expert testimony.
  - Legal Case-Snook, Lloyd November 1986-January 1987, 4 TLS, 2 TD, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 030-010)
    Re: Hook asked to provide testimony.
  - Legal Case, Davis February 1987-February 1988, 1 TLS, 1 legal document (Box-folder 030-011)
  - MAAP July 1997, 1 TLS, 1 TD, 1 certificate (Box-folder 030-012)
    Re: Hook receives certificate for his contributions to MAAP (Medical Academic Advancement Program).
  - MAAP, 1994 June 1994, 1 TMs (Box-folder 030-013)
    Re: Humanities in Medicine Course Syllabus, a course Hook taught.
  - MAAP II: Humanities in Medicine, 1998 June 1998, 1 TMs, 1 TD (Box-folder 030-014)